# Thomas Lee

Lawrenceville, Georgia

(404) 667-7536

github.com/0xkianu

in linkedin.com/in/thomas-lee-43483829

Prospective software engineer with 15+ years of experience in technology as a Database Administrator and Junior Full-Stack Developer. I am a dedicated problem solver and collaborative worker, with experience supporting enterprise-level projects. Seeking a Back-end or Full-stack developer role where I can apply my knowledge and skill working with modern frameworks and programming languages.

#### **Education**

 Digital Crafts Web Development Program Full-Stack Web Development Curriculum

Remote

September 2022 - Apr 2023

Georgia State University

Atlanta, GA

Master of Business Adminstration (GPA: 3.7/4.00)

August 2009 - Dec 2011

Georgia Institute of Technology

**B.S.** Computer Science

August 1998 - Aug 2003

#### Certifications

• Digital Crafts Full-Stack Web Development Certification

April 2023

Atlanta, GA

ISACA Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA)

May 2013

Oracle Database Administrator Certified Professional

Jan 2012

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist, SQL Server

Jan 2005

### Technical Skills

- Languages: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Python, SQL, Pl/SQL, Bash, Perl
- Frameworks/Libraries: React, Redux, Next.js, Express.js, Node.js, Django, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Sequelize, Prisma, Cypress
- Software: Atlassian (Jira, Confluence), Git, AWS (EC2, Lambda, RDS), Heroku, Render, Oracle, SQL Server, Postgresql, Couchdb

## **Experience**

TechJoy Software | Junior Developer

Remote, June 2023 - Present

- Worked as a full stack developer on a number of projects to design and deliver interactive web applications using a variety of technology stacks with languages and frameworks such as Django / Python, Next.js, React, Node.js and Typescript in a CI/CD workflow.
- Worked on development team utilizing Kanban Agile workflow methodology, with regular SCRUM meetings and internal sprint demos.
- Implemented unit and integration tests for all application changes implemented, using Cypress.
- Performed code reviews for interns and other Junior Developers.

#### Riskonnect, Inc. | Senior Database Administrator

Atlanta, GA, January 2024 - Present

- Senior Database Administrator for the leading Risk management software solution provider, with over 2,000 organizations, representing a wide range of industries and spanning six continents.
- Developed internal bash scripts to automate the movement of data across databases and servers for multi-terabyte datasets.
- Developed and deployed hardening scripts for databases, to monitor and audit database access in accordance with SAS 70 / SSAE 16 guidelines
- Deployed and provided code reviews for SQL scripts from database developers, as part of production application releases.
- Maintained open and efficient communication across multiple teams incluing Development, QA, DevOps, Analytics and Infrastructure to meet company goals.

- Lead Oracle and Postgresql database administrator for a global Risk management software solution provider.
- Ensured the integrity and availability of all client databases in all environments (schemas on Oracle databases, schemas on Postgresql databases)
- Installed and configured Oracle 11g, 12g, 13c, 18c, 19c databases on Oracle Linux and Oracle Cloude Infrastructure Exadata environments for OLTP and Data Warehouse environments.
- Installed and configured Postgresql databases on Linux platforms to support data analytics applications
- Designed database security configurations including database users, roles and database objects (tables, packages, stored procedures) to support database auditing, in support of risk management applications.
- Developed shell scripts and PL/SQL jobs to automate adminstrative tasks including backups, maintenance and data migrations.
- Maximized database performance by analyzing SQL and PL/SQL code and implementing database improvements
  or providing recommendations to development teams, including optimizer hints, index recommendations and SQL
  revisions.

### **Projects**

Junior Data Scientist | Discord Chat Bot

January 2024 (in development)

- Designed and developed a python application to scrape and filter user responses in JSON format, from channels in a Discord server.
- Uploaded Discord data into a Chroma DB Vector database and created a pipeline to apply Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) on a Mistrel 7B large language model, enabling the model to answer questions related to the Discord server.
- Technologies: Python, Mistrel 7B LLM, Ollama, Llamaindex, Chroma DB

Junior Developer | Support Local

November 2023 (in development)

- Junior Full-Stack Developer on Support Local, an ecosystem where local business owners can promote their businesses or charities, and consumers can search for deals and support non-profits.
- Collaborated in the front-end and back-end redesign and development of the overhauled website.
- Guided Interns working on the project and provided code reviews to Interns and other Junior Developers
- Technologies: Next.js, Postgresql, Prisma (ORM), Clerk (authentication), Uploadcare (file management), Vercel

Junior Developer | Off Road Fun Finder

September 2023

- Junior Full-Stack Developer on Off Road Fun Finder, an ios / android mobile and web application that allows users to discover off-road tracks, shops, trainers and events.
- Researched and created prototype refactoring of React Hook Forms to Formik.
- Contributed to the documentation of the project codebase on Github.
- Created unit and integration tests using Cypress
- Technologies: React, Django, SQLite, JWT authentication, Uploadcare (file management), Heroku

Senior Database Administrator | Security and Compliance Enhancement

January 2024

- Designed and deployed database objects to support the auditing and storage of user login information, not in accordance with SSAE 16 guidelines.
- Developed triggers and database jobs to monitor and capture users accessing databases with unauthorized logins, and
  also developed shell scripts to create weekly reports of violating logins for all users in all production and UAT databases.

Senior Database Administrator | Database Replication Automation

June 2017

- Designed and developed the framework for scripts to automate the replication of databases, allowing for faster backups, recovery and migration of large databases or data sets.
- Contributed to the redesign of said framework scripts, integrated with Oracle's intelligent backup solution Zero Data Loss Recovery Appliance (ZDLRA), to create a robust system of scripts to automate data replication as a means of backup, recovery and migration.